<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chris Yin</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://chrisyin.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://chrisyin.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Experiment&#58; Movie Annotation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last year, have been working on a small side project to help people understand movies/tv shows better. A lot of times after I watch something, I&amp;rsquo;ll lurk on Wikipedia/IMDB/Reddit etc to find answers to any outstanding questions. Sometimes just I&amp;rsquo;ll casually float around the web to revisit some of the scenes, discover any subtleties I may have missed, or just talk about how awesome/shitty something was. Some notable times I&amp;rsquo;ve done this &amp;ndash; after &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1375666/faq&quot;&gt;Inception&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prometheus2-movie.com/community/forums/42&quot;&gt;Prometheus&lt;/a&gt;, and after every &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/breakingbad&quot;&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/a&gt; episode in the second half of Season 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would spend a fair amount of time collecting bits of information from around the web, consolidating it into my mind to form a cohesive story, explain it to a friend, and then I&amp;rsquo;d be satisfied. But it was a massive time suck and an enormous pain in the ass. To find the info I&amp;rsquo;d have to scour the web &amp;ndash; on one end, going through generic synopses on Wikipedia (usually really high level and poorly written) and then all the way down to crawling through IMDB boards/Reddit (essentially internet forums &amp;ndash; and we know how these are. Have to wade through tons of shit to hopefully find 1 nugget of good info).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get any real answers/insight into questions, some serious internet investigation would have to take place. Sometimes you&amp;rsquo;d find a decent answer on Wikipedia, follow it up with a good comment in Reddit, then have to read someone&amp;rsquo;s take on a random blog post. Once again &amp;ndash; a massive pain in the ass, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy to share the end result with other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a friend, I decided to build a new way to do this. We&amp;rsquo;re on V2 now, but in the meantime &amp;ndash; to quickly test the general thesis of this idea (do people even care about reading more into film/tv shows?), I did an annotation of &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1dwjTCc&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Godfather&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://poetry.rapgenius.com/&quot;&gt;PoetryGenius&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; shared with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://poetry.rapgenius.com/tv-movie-genius&quot;&gt;RapGenius&lt;/a&gt; community. The response was pretty awesome &amp;ndash; got a lot of comments, messages, feedback, and views pretty quickly. Even floated over to popular posts on the home page for some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was pretty cool to share the annotation with other people and see other people care about it. The annotation style on Rapgenius is not exactly how I imagine this working, but it&amp;rsquo;s close enough for a quick test. Going to continue working to finish V2, but in the meantime will do a few more types of annotations and share to see if it continues to resonate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out! &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1dwjTCc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Godfather&amp;rdquo; Annotation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://chrisyin.com/2014/02/03/movie-annotation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisyin.com/2014/02/03/movie-annotation/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Expensive Headphone Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently got some higher end headphones as a gift. While they were awesome, I wanted to make sure I was getting my money&amp;rsquo;s worth, so I looked around. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never been super big on headphones, so this was my first real pass at something nice. For the last few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve just been using whatever headphones came with my cell phone &amp;ndash; most recently the iPhone 5 in ear headphones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/iphone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;iphone5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I started to get into it, I realized I had no idea what I was reading about. Circumaural vs supraural, noise cancelling vs noise isolation &amp;ndash; all meaningless to me. So I read a bit. &lt;a href=&quot;http://thewirecutter.com/reviews/which-headphones-should-i-get/&quot;&gt;Wirecutter has a great overview&lt;/a&gt; on the space, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Headphones#Types&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; is always good too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Case &amp;amp; Criteria&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main use for headphones for work. Calls, blocking others out, trying to focus on what&amp;rsquo;s on hand, etc. From what I read, I knew I didn&amp;rsquo;t want another set of in ear headphones &amp;ndash; I already had Apple for that. And supra-aural was no good, I had a pair a few years ago and they were uncomfortable. Was unsure about noise cancelling vs noise isolation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So came up with this list of things that were important to me &amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blocks Noise&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone who travels and works remotely fairly often, I find myself frequently working in noisy places. Lots of coffee shops, airports, and even when I am in the office/at home, lots of people on calls. It can be super distracting and really suck. Apple in ear headphones do not suffice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comfort&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, I got a pair of supra-aural &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1fc0DB5&quot;&gt;Grado Labs SR60i&lt;/a&gt; headphones a few years back (gift) &amp;ndash; and while the quality of music was amazing, they were not that comfortable. I found after wearing for a few hours, my ears would start to ache. Given the long amounts of time I have my headphones in, comfort was an important factor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needs a mic on it. I&amp;rsquo;m on calls for a large part of the day, and being able to quickly answer calls without taking my headphones off is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Portable&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I travel and move around from place to place a lot. Needs to be easy to bring around places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sound Quality&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, should needs to be good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read a fair amount of reviews and guides on a variety of publications and product reviews on Amazon. The best article I found was this &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&quot;http://thewirecutter.com/reviews/best-300ish-headphone/&quot;&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s Best $300 Over Ear Headphones&lt;/a&gt;. Went to try a few of these out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One note &amp;ndash; There are 2 types of noise reducing headphones &amp;ndash; noise isolation and noise cancellation. Noise isolation means the headphones just cover your ears. Active noise cancellation headphones means there&amp;rsquo;s a mic that listens to external noise and actively tries to cancel it. For noise cancelling headphones, you typically have a battery and a switch to turn on the noise cancellation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1fc1H80&quot;&gt;Sennheiser Momentum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sennheiser.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;momentum&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most acclaimed headphones I found were the Sennheiser Momentums. The reviews were great, and they look amazing. No active noise reduction. All around glowing reviews &amp;ndash; the only real concern voiced online was that they weren&amp;rsquo;t very comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listening to music in these were an absolute delight. The quality of sound was great. But while the sound quality was every bit as good as the reviews mentioned, the comfort issues were equally accurate. They earpads didn&amp;rsquo;t fit over my entire ear, and the headphones felt small on my head. It was immediately apparent that wearing these for long durations of time would be a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Price: $299&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My take: Sound quality is awesome. The look and feel of the product is even better. But the dealbreaker is comfort &amp;ndash; wearing these for long periods of time wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1fc2rKk&quot;&gt;PSB M4U2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/psb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;psb&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These were Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s winner for best pair for $300. Active noise cancellation, and people praised the quality of sound. What was awesome was that you could use the headphones without turning noise cancellation on (unlike some others).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without noise cancelling, the headphones sounded nice. With noise cancelling on, they sounded great. The noise cancelling let you focus on the quality of the sound, which was amazing. Also, there&amp;rsquo;s lots of padding so they&amp;rsquo;re very comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But they are big and heavy. You can definitely feel the extra weight on your head, and they take up a lot of space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Price: $299&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My take: While the sound quality was great, the headphones were far too heavy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1cXfGLs&quot;&gt;Bowers &amp;amp; Wilkins P7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/bowers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bowers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These headphones look a bit different from what I&amp;rsquo;m used to, and I put them on with a bit of bias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But they are surprisingly comfortable. They fit over the entire ear, and they feel solid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t super impressed with the sound quality. It certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t bad, but I like the PSB M4U2&amp;rsquo;s and Sennheiser Momentum better. These also weren&amp;rsquo;t noise cancelling, and I was trying them out in a noisy environment &amp;ndash; I could hear pretty much everybody. Quickly scratched this from the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Price: $399&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My take: Expensive, looks a bit too special for me, and not as good as others in relation to sound quality or noise reduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1duompf&quot;&gt;Audio Technica ATH-ANC9 Quietpoint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/audiotechnica.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;quietpoint&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Audio Technica headphones in general are very well regarded, and the general sentiment is that Audio Technica makes great headphones at a great prices. These in particular had active noise cancellation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you put these on, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice immediately how little you notice. They&amp;rsquo;re really light and by far the most comfortable I had tried up to this point. The noise cancellation worked well &amp;ndash; you could also use the headphones with or without it turned on, which was really nice. Sound quality was nice &amp;ndash; on par or only slightly inferior to Momentum or M4U2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Price: $285&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My take: Sound quality good and comparable to others. Noise cancellation better than PSB&amp;rsquo;s, and much more comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1lO5KFa&quot;&gt;Bose QC15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/bose.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bose&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My sister has these, so I did try &amp;amp; use these more extensively than the others. When I switched them on, I was amazed. These were incredibly good at cancelling out sound &amp;ndash; proved when I was writing this post and I had absolutely no idea there was a group of people talking behind me. Also really light and comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as the Bose haters will note, the sound quality is a bit below average relative to the others. Also, these headphones only work when noise cancellation is turned on &amp;ndash; so if your battery&amp;rsquo;s dead, can&amp;rsquo;t use them. Which sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Price: $299&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My take: What these lack in sound quality is made up with amazing noise cancellation and comfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Winner: Bose QC15&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it came down to it, noise cancellation and comfort trumped sound quality. The Bose headphones, despite the inferior sound quality relative to the others in this list, were by far the most comfortable comfortable its noise cancellation was far better than anything else. Also has a mic to make calls!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For someone like me &amp;ndash; frequently on the go and working in noisy environments, Bose is the way to go. Else, if you&amp;rsquo;re buying headphones to really enjoy music in a quiet environment, I would go with something else - either the Sennheiser Momentum or PSB M4U2.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://chrisyin.com/2014/01/04/expensive-headphone-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisyin.com/2014/01/04/expensive-headphone-review/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apps I Used in 2013</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Following &lt;a href=&quot;http://parislemon.com/post/71774755194/the-apps-i-actually-used-in-2013&quot;&gt;MG&amp;rsquo;s post on the same subject&lt;/a&gt;. Thought it was interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are mine. Tried to rank in terms of usage/importance per category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gmail&lt;br /&gt;
Asana&lt;br /&gt;
Tempo/Google Calendar&lt;br /&gt;
Google Drive&lt;br /&gt;
Dropbox&lt;br /&gt;
Hipchat&lt;br /&gt;
GoToMeeting&lt;br /&gt;
Jira&lt;br /&gt;
Zendesk&lt;br /&gt;
Github&lt;br /&gt;
Google Analytics&lt;br /&gt;
Balsamiq&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sleep Time/Clock&lt;br /&gt;
Google Maps&lt;br /&gt;
Pocket&lt;br /&gt;
Evernote&lt;br /&gt;
Speedtest&lt;br /&gt;
Draft&lt;br /&gt;
Lift&lt;br /&gt;
Penzu&lt;br /&gt;
Line&lt;br /&gt;
Yelp&lt;br /&gt;
IFTTT&lt;br /&gt;
Flixter (Rottentomates)&lt;br /&gt;
Yahoo Sports (Fantasy Basketball)&lt;br /&gt;
Square Cash&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Twitter&lt;br /&gt;
Linkedin&lt;br /&gt;
Instagram&lt;br /&gt;
Buffer&lt;br /&gt;
Tumblr&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandora&lt;br /&gt;
Shazam&lt;br /&gt;
Netflix&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May need to update &lt;a href=&quot;http://chrisyin.com/tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/a&gt;. Happy New Year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://chrisyin.com/2013/12/31/apps-i-used-in-2013/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisyin.com/2013/12/31/apps-i-used-in-2013/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nest Thermostat Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought my folks a Nest over break. The question I hear a lot is &amp;ndash; is it worth the ~$300?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TL;DR - Yes. It&amp;rsquo;s good for now, but not perfect. Review below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/nest.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;nest&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://nest.com/thermostat/life-with-nest-thermostat/&quot;&gt;Nest Thermostat&lt;/a&gt; is a &amp;lsquo;smart&amp;rsquo; thermostat that learns from your habits to reduce wateful spending. Touting features like auto away (turning heat down automatically when you&amp;rsquo;re out), self learning (setting optimal temperatures itself) and more, it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty compelling buy. And not to mention that it looks awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Validation &amp;amp; Installation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you can use the Nest, you have to make sure it&amp;rsquo;s compatible with your house. To find out, you remove the cover of your current thermostat, go to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://widgets.nest.com/compatibility/&quot;&gt;Nest compatibility site&lt;/a&gt; and check a few wires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/nest2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;old-thermostat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case, I had a W, Rh, Y, G, and another tying Rh to Rc. I emailed them in case (&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:photos@nest.com&quot;&gt;photos@nest.com&lt;/a&gt;) and they were pretty quick (within 6 hours) to respond and confirm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the site, I was returned with this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/nest3.png&quot; alt=&quot;diagram&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was unsure of what to do with the Rh to Rc wire, so I left it off. Discovered later that &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/article/How-do-I-install-Nest-if-my-old-thermostat-had-a-short-wire-connecting-Rh-and-Rc&quot;&gt;it wasn&amp;rsquo;t necessary&lt;/a&gt; (aside &amp;ndash; found a fair amount of people with the same question, so would have been helpful to include in setup instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/nest4.png&quot; alt=&quot;install&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installation was pretty straightforward &amp;ndash; turn off the electricity via circuit box, remove old thermostat, screw in Nest plate, plug in wires, and then put the Nest on top of it. 15-20 min.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once it&amp;rsquo;s on, configuration was easy &amp;ndash; it takes you through a few setup screens &amp;ndash; name your Nest, set the network, time zone, default temp, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this was done, next was to link my phone. Created a Nest account on their &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.nest.com/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, and it auto linked my account to my Nest based on the network. Again, pretty smooth &amp;amp; easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using the Nest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although everything had been easy up to this point, learning more about using Nest was a bit lacking. Outside of learning by pushing buttons, Nest has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.nest.com/community/help-with-nest&quot;&gt;Community&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/thermostat/&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; page on their site. While these pages provided some info, I was still hoping to get into more detail on all their features and how to optimally configure/use it. There&amp;rsquo;s almost nothing useful in the box, and what I &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/article/An-introduction-to-learning&quot;&gt;found&lt;/a&gt; on the web wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the cool features &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/article/An-introduction-to-learning&quot;&gt;Learning&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/article/How-does-Auto-Schedule-learn&quot;&gt;Scheduling&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/article/What-is-Early-On&quot;&gt;Early On&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/article/How-does-the-Nest-Leaf-work&quot;&gt;Leaf&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/article/How-to-read-my-Energy-History-on-the-Nest-Learning-Thermostat&quot;&gt;Energy Savings&lt;/a&gt; and more, are things that develop over time. To learn more, I had to look into a forum or community thread &amp;ndash; it would have been helpful to get information straight from Nest &amp;ndash; list of features, how/when to use X feature, when to check back in to make sure it&amp;rsquo;s being used properly, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this info is up front and center as opposed to hidden in support, users will better understand what Nest is doing and how to get the most out of it. While I understand the goal of Nest is to &amp;lsquo;set it and forget it&amp;rsquo;, it would have been helpful to spell out the features for users so they don&amp;rsquo;t have to go digging through the the forums to find the answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI/UX&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize this is a fairly large upgrade from the standard thermostat in terms of aesthetic/usability &amp;ndash; and although the UX is nice, I was a bit disappointed in the UI, both on the device and the apps (&lt;a href=&quot;https://home.nest.com/&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/id464988855?mt=8&quot;&gt;mobile&lt;/a&gt;). While you have to take the 2 &amp;frac12; stars and poor reviews with a grain of salt, the apps could definitely use some improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the one area that scared me a bit. After initially setting up the Nest, we left town for a day. Upon return, I was excited to turn on the Nest &amp;amp; pre-heat the house remotely &amp;ndash; but the app said the Nest was offline. After getting back and checking &amp;ndash; Nest having trouble connecting to the network because of low battery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Totally unaware there was even a battery (thought it powered through the wall), I went online to figure out what was going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/nest5.png&quot; alt=&quot;images&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Found this on the support page and it &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/article/Intermittent-low-battery-or-connectivity-issues-with-thermostat-software-4-0&quot;&gt;lead to this article&lt;/a&gt;. With no steps to fix, had to search a bit more and found &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/article/What-s-the-mini-USB-port-on-the-back-of-the-display-for&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; had to recharge Nest through an outlet so we could use &amp;amp; reconnect in the interim (next up was &lt;a href=&quot;http://shaunmerrigan.info/site-news/nest-thermostat-battery-charge-problem-and-solution/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; if it didn&amp;rsquo;t work). Let it charge for ~1hr and set it back on the wall. Haven&amp;rsquo;t had a problem since, but the lack of clear steps for a resolution left me a bit uneasy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While perusing the support pages during this time, I found a few frustrated people with Nest&amp;rsquo;s seemingly lack of care for support issues. With only a support email alias and no direct number, I can see why. While email only support is fairly common for startups, not sure if this is a good approach for home consumer products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seems like I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one with some issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;huh. Got a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nest&quot;&gt;@nest&lt;/a&gt;. PG&amp;amp;E bill is 3x higher than last month. Clearly it needs some learning ...&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Micah Baldwin (@micah) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/micah/statuses/420271372980326401&quot;&gt;January 6, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;




&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Urg. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nest&quot;&gt;@nest&lt;/a&gt; is playing up, needs a software update, and the web site doesn’t explain how to force an update to ver 4.01. Anyone know?&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; John Borthwick (@Borthwick) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Borthwick/statuses/420756098761494528&quot;&gt;January 8, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Still, Nest will need to better educate customers and ramp up support to avoid being blamed for problems it didn’t cause. Otherwise, customer issues like these could shake confidence in Nest&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2014/01/06/nest-4-0-firmware-battery-problems/&quot;&gt;via Techcrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But if it&amp;rsquo;s causing problems for even adept users like myself, this could be a big problem in the long run for the company.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/nest-thermostat-problem-2014-1&quot;&gt;via Business Insider&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Nest-Learning-Thermostat-Generation-T200577/product-reviews/B009GDHYPQ/ref=cm_cr_pr_hist_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;filterBy=addOneStar&amp;amp;showViewpoints=0&amp;amp;sortBy=bySubmissionDateDescending&quot;&gt;Another link to some pretty poor Amazon reviews (obviously, take these with a grain of salt).&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a good experience with Nest and would generally recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s clear the Nest guys spent a lot of time building a beautiful product. However, the experience as a whole feels incomplete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aesthetics and functionality of the product are amazing and undoubtedly a step up from a traditional thermostat. But as for continuing to support and help users maximize usage of the product after installation, Nest could use some improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By simply adding a detailed user manual so users know how they&amp;rsquo;re benefitting from Nest&amp;rsquo;s features and providing a better support site or line, they could dramatically improve the overall experience. Otherwise, Nest runs the risk of being perceived as an expensive remote control for your thermostat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you&amp;rsquo;re into new toys and want to upgrade &amp;ndash; Nest is perfect for you. But I think for now, Nest will remain an expensive toy in consumers' eyes until it has spent more time in the market proving that it is worth the cost.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://chrisyin.com/2013/12/23/nest-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisyin.com/2013/12/23/nest-review/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Freemium Doesn't Always Work in B2B</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a follow up post to &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1hxzntZ&quot;&gt;Building for the Enterprise&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For startups, the business space may seem like a gold mine. There are problems everywhere you look, customers will pay you to fix them, and there&amp;rsquo;s not millions of other startups competing with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these attributes can make the business space attractive, not all problems are applicable to every business. Entrepreneurs must understand the types of problems they are solving in relation to the priorities of the companies they&amp;rsquo;re targeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Companies are filled with problems. Productivity, collaboration, operations, hiring, legal, sales, support, etc. But depending on the stage of the business &amp;ndash; early, growth, pre-IPO, public, etc. &amp;ndash; each one will have different priorities (in regards to problems that need to be solved).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, take an early stage company &amp;ndash; their focus may be marketing &amp;amp; sales. In this case, the priority is to find a solution to help them manage deals. A growth stage company&amp;rsquo;s main focus may be managing support &amp;ndash; so they&amp;rsquo;ll be looking for a support tool. And so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to determine if a problem fits a company&amp;rsquo;s stage, simply ask &amp;ndash; is this a C-level problem? C-level issues are problems important enough that a CEO/exec will prioritize it. Usually only then will it get solved in a timely manner; otherwise, it may not get solved in a time frame that you can stomach (or afford).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&quot;http://tcrn.ch/18MuCue&quot;&gt;Xpenser&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://tcrn.ch/18Muzyn&quot;&gt;Coupa&lt;/a&gt;, we made and sold an expense management solution &amp;ndash; a web/mobile app that helped companies create, approve and reimburse their employees' expense reports. More than making it easier for employees to capture their expenses &amp;amp; get reimbursed, our software streamlines the reimbursement process &amp;ndash; helping companies reduce the operational cost of processing and managing lots of expense reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since our solution reduces cost, we have to target companies whose priority is cost reduction. Typically smaller companies are more focused on the top line (sales), while larger companies can also focus on the bottom line (cost).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get these large enterprises, our strategy (product, sales, marketing) has to reflect how they buy software &amp;ndash; through RFP&amp;rsquo;s, direct sales, analyst reports, etc. We need an enterprise roadmap, the right messaging, and an enterprise sales team in order to maximize our ROI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our previous model &amp;ndash; freemium/bottom up &amp;ndash;  was not the most effective way to reach our customer. While we aimed for large deals, this model attracted consumers and SMB&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ndash; because the freemium model was akin to how consumers/SMB&amp;rsquo;s bought software, not how large companies bought software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for many of the SMB&amp;rsquo;s that we did engage &amp;ndash; they sale either dragged on for too long or eventually petered out &amp;ndash; because even though we had gotten into the business, that particular problem wasn&amp;rsquo;t a C-level problem or a business priority. Our strategy didn&amp;rsquo;t match our target customer&amp;rsquo;s stage or how they bought software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So before you take the popular sentiment of building a freemium SaaS, make sure you understand the problem you&amp;rsquo;re solving and what stage of company is interested &amp;ndash; and then build your strategy around that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://chrisyin.com/2013/12/21/freemium-doesn%27t-always-work-in-b2b/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisyin.com/2013/12/21/freemium-doesn%27t-always-work-in-b2b/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building for the Enterprise</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A little over a year ago, I joined &lt;a href=&quot;http://tcrn.ch/18MuCue&quot;&gt;Xpenser&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; a startup building expense management tools for businesses and individuals. We were 4 years old, bootstrapped, small (3 full time + interns), ~85K users and ~150 paying customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was my first time building for businesses. I studied and learned about building product for companies, how to sell, marketing, support, scaling, recruiting, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 6 months later, we were acquired by &lt;a href=&quot;http://tcrn.ch/18Muzyn&quot;&gt;Coupa&lt;/a&gt;, a spend management company, to help run &amp;amp; build upon their existing expense management business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we started at Coupa, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d be doing the same thing I was doing at Xpenser, but just at a different company. The setting would be different, but the goals were the same &amp;ndash; build the best expense management solution for the businesses. At the time we joined, Coupa was 6 years old, had raised ~$50M in venture capital, ~150 people, and 400+ paying customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was wrong. Even though both times we were solving the same problem &amp;amp; selling to companies, the lessons I learned didn&amp;rsquo;t apply universally. At Xpenser we were selling to businesses; at Coupa, we were selling to the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As a student of the startup game, both times (at Xpenser &amp;amp; Coupa) I went to the web to learn from founders/entrepreneurs. Both times I found little helpful information, and in many cases, what I did find turned out to just be plain wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of startup advice I found on the web was directed at consumer startups. And that made sense &amp;ndash; for a startup whose customers are other businesses, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to keep gushing your mistakes in a public forum. That kind of information will kill you in a sale. Opacity and boilerplate press releases were safer than honest blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s hard to find good information on the web for startups to learn about building for businesses. For what I did find &amp;ndash; there seemed to be a general misconception &amp;ndash; B2B does not always mean enterprise. There is some gray area, but for the most part, there is a distinction between building for businesses and buidling for the enterprise. There are difference, and those differences should shape your strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After serving and building for all types of businesses at both Xpenser &amp;amp; Coupa, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a bit about the space, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned here. &lt;a href=&quot;http://eepurl.com/DdF7n&quot;&gt;Click here to subscribe&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://chrisyin.com/2013/12/14/building-for-the-enterprise/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisyin.com/2013/12/14/building-for-the-enterprise/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Leadership</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What is it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ability to get someone to follow you, even if only out of curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do people believe you have the interest of the company over yours?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do they believe you can execute?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you have all 3, you&amp;rsquo;ve got it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/sqI7fa04atc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://chrisyin.com/2013/10/19/leadership/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisyin.com/2013/10/19/leadership/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Working Hard &amp; Not Getting Anything Done</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you are hunting elephants, don&amp;rsquo;t get distracted chasing rabbits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;em&gt;T. Boone Pickens&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years I&amp;rsquo;ve been a big inbox zero guy. I rigorously maintained all of my inboxes and other web services (pocket, feedly, evernote, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, if you didn&amp;rsquo;t manage your online services, they were useless. Then they were toys &amp;ndash; fun to play with, but don&amp;rsquo;t provide any real utility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, I was getting a fair amount of emails and I was able to manage. Since I started at Coupa, it shot up at least 3 fold and I was drowning in a deluge of emails. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep up. I needed a new system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I was listening to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iqUG2_cmZ6I&quot;&gt;PandoMonthly with Chris Sacca&lt;/a&gt; (embedded below). An awesome talk all around &amp;ndash; but the point that that stood out to me was the notion of offense vs. defense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take an email inbox. An inbox is really just a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/shellen/status/228202415789334528&quot;&gt;public todo list&lt;/a&gt; that anybody can put things on. You can easily spend all day ticking off your emails and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to feel accomplished and like you&amp;rsquo;re getting a lot done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s a false sense of accomplishment. By spending your efforts checking off tasks that anyone can give you, there&amp;rsquo;s no coherence around your tasks. You keep working aimlessly and doing everyone&amp;rsquo;s else&amp;rsquo;s bidding but your own. It&amp;rsquo;s the ultimate exercise in feeling busy, but not actually doing anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Prior, I was always impeccable at getting my emails done. I always emailed back. I always followed up at least 3 times. The more useless emails that I responded to, the more useless work came into my life. I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize any of this at the time &amp;ndash; I felt like I was getting shit done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it fell apart with the addition of Coupa emails, I started trying to figure out a new way to manage all my emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s when I watched the video below and it opened my eyes to what I was actually doing. I felt accomplished, but I was really just keeping busy doing work for other people. I was only making marginal &amp;ndash; if any &amp;ndash; progress on my own goals. That&amp;rsquo;s why every time I turned off my email and worked in a dark corner, I felt extremely productive. Otherwise I always felt like I was getting stuff done, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like I was doing anything or making any progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I realized that in order to make real progress, I had to give up on the ridiculous notion of inbox zero. I took a step back, planned out some goals, milestones, and got to work. The endless slew of inbound emails were ignored unless they fit in with my set goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s been incredibly cathartic. Yes, my inbox is exploding, but I&amp;rsquo;m making real, tangible progress on the different goals I&amp;rsquo;ve set. I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to make more progress than before, find more free time, and everything else in my inbox is still going on perfectly fine without my response. Amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This thought expands further than simply managing email. It&amp;rsquo;s a principle to remember in any situation &amp;ndash; make sure you&amp;rsquo;re always playing offense. There are endless amounts of noise in the world trying to distract you. It can feel productive to work on clearing the noise, but it&amp;rsquo;s a waste of effort &amp;ndash; and a futile one. The only way to truly advance on what&amp;rsquo;s important is to ignore the noise, buckle down, and push your goals to completion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;




&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/iqUG2_cmZ6I&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://chrisyin.com/2013/08/27/pretending-to-work/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisyin.com/2013/08/27/pretending-to-work/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The First Step To Becoming A Leader</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What is a leader?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A leader is someone who drives a group of people towards a common goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaders come in all different flavors, but the best leaders all have a few things in common &amp;ndash; they have a clear vision and they are the drivers that push it all forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does it take to become a leader? Charisma, salesmanship, product sense, etc. are all pieces of it, but not the key element. At the core, a leader is someone who simply makes good decisions for the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I believe that everyone knows what a good decision looks like. People either explicitly know what it is, or they are able to &amp;ldquo;feel&amp;rdquo; when a decision is right. Intuition is still always there as a fail safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then why isn&amp;rsquo;t everyone a leader?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes down to it, most people don&amp;rsquo;t speak their minds. They stifle their own voice and default to the majority. The majority must know better, be smarter, have more experience, etc. This can be especially true if you&amp;rsquo;re in a group full of people smarter than you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To become a leader, all you have to do is start speaking your mind. That simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking your mind is how you learn. You force yourself to have an opinion, take a side, and voice it publicly. If you&amp;rsquo;re consistently right, people will recognize this and you will quickly evolve into the decision making authority and leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when you speak up, you might not always be right. In fact, when you start to really speak your mind, there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance you&amp;rsquo;ll often be wrong. When this happens, it can certainly be easy to hide behind silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re wrong, people might call you an idiot. And in the short term, you might actually feel like an idiot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. When you put yourself out there, you expose your actual thoughts. You create a voice for yourself as well as subjecting your thought process to criticism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take in the criticism, recalibrate, and try again. You can tweak what was wrong before, and constantly iterate your thought process to success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you say nothing, you never put yourself out there. By not exposing what you think, you never challenge your own thought process, your ideas, and your beliefs. It&amp;rsquo;s easier to hide behind silence than subject yourself to the risk of ridicule. Over time, however, those that speak out will continue to improve and others will remain static.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After constantly interating and optimizing your thought process, you&amp;rsquo;ll start to hone your instincts and begin making the right decisions. By this point you&amp;rsquo;ll have a voice for yourself in the group, have confidence in your opinions, and have naturally evolved into a leader for your group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve typically been pretty outspoken. And while this might all seem like common sense, I found that once I started paying attention to myself, I realized I was subconsciously defaulted to the majority on a several things that I actually had an opinions on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I caught myself and changed my behavior, but I wouldve never realized that I was keeping quiet until I started to explicitly watch my own behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give it a shot, would love to hear thoughts or if you&amp;rsquo;ve had a similar experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://chrisyin.com/2013/08/20/becoming-a-leader/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisyin.com/2013/08/20/becoming-a-leader/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>To Improve Your Work, Stop Working</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been in a depression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a mental depression, but a depression in regards to personal development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I define personal development as doing things that you enjoy working on in your free time. Not just anything, but things you actively work on to get better at without any external motivation to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve spent all of my time working on my day job instead of taking the time to do any personal development. Things like reading, writing, or working on personal side projects that don&amp;rsquo;t make any money :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By spending all of my time working, I&amp;rsquo;m actually getting worse at work. And I&amp;rsquo;m not getting any better at my personal interests. Doubly bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt; 


&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get sucked into work. They pay you. Projects are handed to you. You feel productive when you work on something. You know what you have to deliver. Strategy and goals are set for you &amp;ndash; you just have to execute. Things are relatively straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too often these factors lead people to spend all of time working. With non-stop work emails as the new norm and every email marked as &lt;em&gt;URGENT!!!&lt;/em&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to feel like it&amp;rsquo;s irresponsible to do anything other than work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with constant working is that while you might feel like you&amp;rsquo;re being productive, you&amp;rsquo;re only making incremental improvements. By constantly working on the same thing &amp;ndash; you close your mind and limit your ability to think and grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Most innovation comes from outside of the company.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;  -&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inc.com/allison-fass/tony-hsieh-zappos-growth-strategies.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tony Hsieh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of Zappos&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What we know about the brain is that the brain does not work on forming its connections while we are focused on the idea.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;  -&lt;a href=&quot;http://mixergy.com/course-cheat-sheet-deliberate-innovation/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Debra Kaye&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Founder of Lucule Consulting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to innovate and make real strides in your career/ life, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to lift yourself out of the day to day tactical work and just &lt;em&gt;do other things&lt;/em&gt;. Finish a book, write a blog post, volunteer, or work on a side project. Get out of the building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By spending time applying your mind to other problems, you can learn and draw inspiration from outside. When you are focused on 1 problem, you develop tunnel vision. Your thinking narrows, and your thoughts can get boxed in. When you venture outside and let go, you&amp;rsquo;re able to re-open your mind and see things in a novel way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of work, by developing other skills, you simply become a more valuable person. You learn new skill set, open your mind, and become a much more versatile thinker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a personal anecdote, I&amp;rsquo;ve found my best ideas come from moments where my mind is farthest from the problem at hand. If I get stuck on something, I&amp;rsquo;ll start writing a post or start working on a side project and the answer serendipitously strikes me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difficulty for me is finding the right balance. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly fond of the way Jeff Atwood describes it in his post, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2009/03/sharpening-the-saw.html&quot;&gt;Sharpening the Saw&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;A guy who stumbled into a lumberjack. The lumberjack is feverishly sawing at a very large tree. The lumberjack was sawing and sawing, yet going nowhere. The saw was about as sharp as a butter knife. So, he says to the lumberjack, &amp;ldquo;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help noticing how hard you are working on that tree, but going nowhere.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lumberjack replies with sweat dripping off of his brow, &amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;hellip;I know.&amp;rdquo; The bystander replies and says, &amp;ldquo;But your saw is so dull that it couldn&amp;rsquo;t possibly cut through anything.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;I know&amp;rdquo;, says the lumberjack, &amp;ldquo;but I am too busy sawing to take time to sharpen my saw.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if the post is meant to be read this way &amp;ndash; but to me, working is the tactical action of sawing away at the tree. Personal development is the act of sharpening the saw. In order to maximize your efficiency, you must find a balance between the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Constantly re-assess yourself, and be ruthlessly intellectually honest. Spend too much time sawing away and you never make a real impact. Spend too much time sharpening the saw, and you never get anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So force yourself to take time and do other things. Especially in startup, it can be hard to pry yourself away from all of the critical things happening. But make sure to take time every day or at least every week to let go of work and focus on building your own personal skill set and interests. You will end up serving not only your company, but also yourself much better in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://chrisyin.com/2013/08/01/sharpening-the-saw/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisyin.com/2013/08/01/sharpening-the-saw/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>